scansafe.net 2009-06-01

# ScanSafe, The World's Leading Provider of SaaS Web Security

## _Privacy Policy_

**General  
** This is the Privacy Policy of ScanSafe Limited.  You may contact ScanSafe directly using any of the communication means outlined at the end of this statement.

As a world leader in Internet security technology, ScanSafe understands your desire to protect personal information.  We at ScanSafe are committed to safeguarding the privacy of visitors to our website and users of our services. Please read the following Privacy Policy carefully before using the ScanSafe website.  If you use the ScanSafe website, you will be bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy. This policy may change from time to time so you should check it frequently.  All updates will be published at this site.

ScanSafe will not track or collect any information about you, your data except as we disclose in this Privacy Policy or as you specifically authorise.  Whenever you give us personal data, you are consenting to its collection and use in accordance with this Privacy Policy. We will not share your personal information for marketing or any other purposes without your consent unless required by law.

**Scope of this Privacy Policy  
** This policy covers how ScanSafe treats personal information that ScanSafe collects and receives, including information related to your past use of ScanSafe products and services.  Personal information is information about you that is personally identifiable like your name, address, email address, or phone number, and that is not otherwise publicly available.

This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that ScanSafe does not own or control, or to people that ScanSafe does not employ or manage.

**Cookies  
** A cookie is a piece of text that gets entered into the memory of your browser by a website, allowing the website to store information on a user's machine and later retrieve it.

At times during your use of the ScanSafe website, we transmit ScanSafe cookies to the hard drive of your computer.  These cookies assign your Web browser a unique series of numbers, letters, or characters that enable ScanSafe's servers to recognize and identify your Web browser when you are using the ScanSafe website.

Cookies are in no way linked to any personally identifiable information.  If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use the website, although some areas may be functionally limited.  
For every search request you submit you view while using the ScanSafe website, the ScanSafe software transmits and stores the following information from your computer to ScanSafe:

  * your IP address, which may include a domain name
  * general information about your browser
  * general information about your computer's operating system
  * your ScanSafe cookie number
  * the date and time the above information is logged.

All of the above information is logged together in a single data string for each search you submit. Each string is logged in our database in the chronological order received from our hundreds of thousands of users.

**Web Beacons  
** ScanSafe may use Web Beacons - also known as single pixel or clear GIFs - on our web site to analyse traffic patterns such as the frequency of use of particular parts of the site.  The data collected helps us learn what information is of most interest to our customers and what offers our customers would most like to see.  If you do not want to assist ScanSafe in improving its Web site, you "can-opt" of this Web site analysis by disabling JavaScript on your computer.  If you disable JavaScript, some of the features on our Web site may not work.

**Does ScanSafe collect personally identifiable information?  
** In general, you can use the ScanSafe website without telling us who you are or giving any personal information about yourself.

If you e-mail ScanSafe, we may store copies of such e-mail or similar communications between you and ScanSafe.  This can result in the collection of your e-mail address or other personally identifiable information you may have in your e-mail text, addresses, or other fields, as well as the collection of the your IP address, the Internet or other routing of your communication, and the date and time of your communication.  We do not attempt to correlate this information to your ScanSafe cookie number or your usage unless responding to your inquiry requires us to do so.

Although these information logs may contain personally identifiable information, ScanSafe does not attempt to correlate cookie numbers or usage to your e-mail address and does not attempt to determine the identity of any ScanSafe user by analysing this information, except as required by subpoenas, court orders or legal requirements.

All transmissions between you and ScanSafe, including e-mails, URLs, cookie identification numbers, search requests, and any personally identifiable information they might contain, pass through many third party machines, operating systems, programs, browsers, Web servers, networks, routers, Ethernet switches, ISPs, proxy servers, intranets, the public telephone systems, or other devices, any of which may create activity logs containing such transmissions.

The ScanSafe website is not directed at individuals under 13 years of age, and we do not intend to collect any personally identifiable information from such individuals.

**What does ScanSafe do with the information it collects?  
** Information about visits to the ScanSafe website is used to provide the ScanSafe services, to improve our services, and to provide anonymous reporting for internal and external clients.

ScanSafe may contact you by e-mail to respond to comments, feedback, and customer service inquiries you submit.  We do not disclose your e-mail address to business partners or to anyone other than employees and agents working for or on behalf of ScanSafe, except as required by subpoenas, court orders, or legal requirements.

We may use IP addresses to diagnose problems with our servers and to administer our website.  Your IP address also is used by ScanSafe to gather broad demographic information, such as your general geographic location and Internet Service Provider.  IP addresses are further used to help determine the number of ScanSafe users.  This demographic information may also be used by ScanSafe to analyze aggregate Web usage behavior.  We may also use this information to block IP addresses where there is a breach of the terms and conditions for use of the ScanSafe website.

In addition, we may disclose personally-identifiable and information: (i) to third parties when we have reason to believe that disclosing the information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) our rights or property, other members or users of the ScanSafe website, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities; and (ii) to third parties when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.

As a global company, we have international sites and users all over the world. When you give us personal data, that data may be sent electronically to servers anywhere in the world and may be used, stored and processed anywhere in the world, including countries outside the European Economic Area. Whenever and wherever we collect, process or use personal data, we take steps to ensure that it is treated securely and in accordance with our privacy policy.

We employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf, such as technical support services.  To perform those functions, it may be necessary for them to obtain access to ScanSafe's databases and servers, which may contain personally identifying information about users.  They may not use such access or information for any purpose other than that for which they are retained.

In the event that ScanSafe or substantially all of its assets are sold or acquired, all information collected by ScanSafe would be transferred to the acquiring party.  In any such transfer, however, such information would remain subject to any applicable terms and conditions, including the terms of this Privacy Policy and any amendment thereto.

**How is your information protected?  
** Access to private and confidential data on our systems is limited to only those employees with a specific need to retrieve this information.  ScanSafe uses commercially reasonable computer security safeguards to protect its databases and servers against risks of loss, unauthorized access, destruction, misuse, modification, or inadvertent or improper disclosure of data.  These risks, however, cannot be completely eliminated and ScanSafe therefore cannot guarantee complete security of any information you transmit to us, and this information is transmitted at your own risk.

ScanSafe also segregates certain personally identifiable information provided by you.  Any e-mail address you chose to provide is stored in a database.  Your web requests are stored on a separate database and server that can be accessed only by a limited number of ScanSafe employees.

**Data collection and use practices by other businesses we do not control  
** When you click on links to other websites, those websites may attach a cookie to your hard drive and may collect information about you.  ScanSafe makes no claims or representations about what those websites do or do not collect about you.  Please review any terms of use and privacy policies of those other businesses to learn about their data collection and data use practices.

You acknowledge and agree that ScanSafe is not responsible for any content, advertising, products, or other materials on the websites (whether co-branded with the ScanSafe logo or not) of or available from other businesses that we do not control.  You further acknowledge that ScanSafe shall not be responsible or liable, directly or indirectly, for any damage or loss caused by or in connection with use of or reliance on any such content, goods or services available on or through any such site or resource.

ScanSafe may report any activity it suspects violates any law or regulation to appropriate law enforcement officials, regulators, or other third parties.  To cooperate with governmental requests, to protect ScanSafe's systems and users, to ensure the integrity and operation of ScanSafe's business and systems, or in response to subpoenas, court orders, or legal requirements, ScanSafe may access and disclose any information it considers necessary or appropriate, including user contact details, IP addressing and traffic information, posted content, and Web usage paths.  By using the ScanSafe website you expressly consent to the foregoing use and disclosure.

**Notification of changes  
** This privacy policy was last updated on 1 August 2006.  We reserve the right to amend or vary this policy at any time and the revised policy will apply from the date posted on the ScanSafe website.  You accept that by doing this, ScanSafe has provided you with sufficient notice of the amendment or variation.

**ScanSafe contact information  
** ScanSafe has designated a Privacy Officer who is accountable for ScanSafe's compliance with the privacy practices described in this policy.  If you have any questions or comments concerning this policy, please contact us using one of the options below:

_Postal mail_

:  
Privacy Officer  
ScanSafe Limited  
198 High Holborn  
London, WC1V 7BD  
United Kingdom

Email: [privacy@scansafe.com](mailto:privacy@scansafe.com)
